Traditionally, an essay or degree project usually consists of these main parts.
In this video I talk about the first part, introduction and purpose.
The introduction is usually about one to one and a half pages.
There you tell the reader what kind of relevant problem you have found when you have read previous research in the form of primary sources.
That is, examined articles published in scientific journals or dissertations.
To tell the reader what kind of problems you have found is also called problem formulation.
It means the same thing and just means describing a problem.
For example, there is previous research, but there is no knowledge of a special thing.
In other words, you have discovered a knowledge gap.
Here it is important that you underpake your arguments with the support of primary sources.
However, remember that the introduction must not be too long.
Briefly tell us about these sources but save the longer descriptions for the section on the purpose.
It is enough if you show that your study is based on a scientific basis and not on your own opinion.
Another error in the introduction is to describe the problem too broad and unclear.
It is not enough to only point out a general problem area.
You have to specify what your study is all about.
The reader should not be forced to guess what problems or lack of knowledge you have discovered when you have read in the area.
This example describes an appreciated business, but the reader may find it difficult to understand what is the study's real problem area.
By adding a precise text, with references to articles and/or dissertations, the study's research problems become much clearer.
We now see that the research problem is that there is a knowledge slot regarding open preschools' work to support parents.
Another error is to focus on yourself too much in the introduction.
Admittedly, it may be of interest to the reader to know something about you.
However, there is no reason that you write an introductory background story based on your personal experiences.
You can briefly mention that you have your own experience in the field of study.
However, your problem formulation, that is, the knowledge gap you have discovered, should be based on scientific primary sources.
Once the reader has taken note of your introduction, he or she should think:
"This is a relevant and important problem of public interest and someone should conduct a study to create knowledge that can help to solve this problem."
A perfect introduction creates this feeling in the reader :-)
For your purpose, tell the reader what you have for your essay or your degree project.
You may also have two or three issues to further clarify and specify your intentions.
The purpose and issues must be about the problem you describe in your introduction.
A common beginner error in the purpose is to write that the study's purpose is to conduct a survey.
The purpose is rather to create knowledge.
You want to help clog the knowledge gap regarding the problem you describe in your introduction.
Another error is that the student believes that the issues should look like interview questions.
It is a common mistake to believe that the issues should be addressed to individuals.
Instead, they should be designed more overall and addressed to what the study intends to investigate.
Do not write: "What do you think as an employee of this company about management's investments in skills development?".
Instead, write a more comprehensive issue that affects the study's implementation.
For example: "What perceptions does employees have about investments in skills development?".
A common mistake is to neglect with words and concepts.
You cannot vary these anyway because it confuses the reader and contributes to poor quality.
Stick to these.
You can write briefly.
Save definitions and longer descriptions for the section on the purpose.
Another error is to use information and arguments that do not belong in the field.
Let me give a concrete example.
An essay in business administration can not only use articles and dissertations that deal with memory research, right?
Furthermore, you probably cannot use theories and concepts from the field of literary science.
Therefore, consider which academic unit or institution to which your essay or degree project belongs.
Then use information, scientific sources, words and concepts that show the reader that your study belongs in this area.
Another error is to discuss the method in detail.
In nine cases out of ten, you can remove this information from the introduction and purpose.
In this example, the student does not write that there is completely lacking research.
Instead, the student writes that there seems to be few studies focusing on what the student's essay is about.
Here is another example where a student does not claim that there is no completely lack of research in the field.
Instead, the student writes that there seems to be a need for Swedish studies in the area.
Another beginner's error is to get stuck for too long in the reading.
Admittedly, you must read articles, dissertations, reports, and so on to get acquainted with the area.
It is an important introductory phase of your work on writing your essay or your degree project.
But for God's sake, never hesitate to interrupt this reading on time and for further with writing.
You do not need to read and understand every document published in the field.
This is not a must to write the introduction and purpose.
It's so easy to end up on time, don't let it happen to you.
Finally, let me remind you that all these are my recommendations.
Other teachers, supervisors and examiners are likely to have partly or completely different views on what applies.
In other words, it is your responsibility to find out what applies to the course you read.
You must find out what instructions, templates and grading criteria apply to the essay or thesis work you write.
For example, in some courses, students do not need to use any formal theory, while on others it is a requirement.
I also recall that you can download and read old essays.
Partly via essay.se and partly through the digital archive that is shortened Diva.
Try to see in the first place how previous students on your course has done.
Read instructions and grading criteria and if you have received a template you should use it.
Click the Gilla button and be happy to subscribe to my Youtube channel.
Also, write some comments you are busy if you have questions or your own tips.
Bye for now!